<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<post>
  <author>gerardo</author>
  <title>Wed Night Race at AYC</title>
  <description />
  <content>&lt;p&gt;I got invited to the Austin Yatch Club for their Wed Night Sunfish/Laser Race. I took my friend Dave with me and used a two-boat trailer thanks to Bubba Horner of LCYC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were at least 15 Sunfishes and 10 Lasers. There were five starts each for Sunfish and Laser and they were staggered. The start sequence was a bit different than what I'm used to at the LCYC races. You get 2 beeps at 2 minute, a beep at 1 min. A beep at 30 seconds. A beep at 10 seconds, a beep at 9 seconds, 8 seconds all the way to start. And a few got called for early start. [more]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The course was set up so that the Race Committee and the starting pin was placed between the windward mark and the downwind mark. On the downwind leg, you can pass on the right of the starting pin or the left of the RC boat but not in between. You only get to pass between the RC boat and the starting pin during the start and the finish. This way you don't collide with the Lasers because they are starting just after the Sunfishes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This race is a great way to improve your starting skills. The line from the RC boat to the starting pin was very narrow (about 7 boat lengths) for that many sailboats and everyone was cramped at the RC boat end. You really have to be aggressive to get a good start. And with such a short course, pretty much everyone is rounding the windward mark at the same time. So again, everyone was cramped there. So many sailors yelling "Starboard". Out of five starts I was lucky to experience fighting for the winward mark twice with every body. The other 3, I got left behind at the start. This really made me feel I need to work on my starts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another nice feature of the race is that they they don't wait for everyone to finish. If you get left behind, you can skip the downwind mark and not get a finish and head back to the finish mark while everyone else is finishing. If you are way behind and don't skip the downwind mark, you won't have time to set up for the next start. And that happened to me on my first start. So I opted to not get a finish twice so I can set up for a good start at the next start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The race was scheduled at 6pm but we did not start until about 6:25pm. But with such a fast-pace race, we got 5 starts and still finished before it got dark.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trip was well worth it driving from Canyon Lake. It made me realize the need to practice my starts. And I got to see firsthand Lasers doing their roll tacks. With the wind being light, I saw one or two Sunfishes sailing by the lee on the downwind leg. I will definitely rig my Sunfish for this first thing tomorrow morning!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have started racing Sunfish two months ago and I recommend this race to every Sunfish and Laser sailor wishing to improve his/her racing skill.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  <ispublished>True</ispublished>
  <isdeleted>False</isdeleted>
  <iscommentsenabled>False</iscommentsenabled>
  <pubDate>2011-09-22 08:15:00</pubDate>
  <lastModified>2011-09-23 00:28:32</lastModified>
  <raters>0</raters>
  <rating>0</rating>
  <slug>Wed-Night-Race-at-AYC</slug>
  <tags />
  <comments />
  <categories>
    <category>df52eb8a-0414-4912-b82a-a7d7b3051529</category>
    <category>49f15f9c-e8a9-4905-951e-22502dd9d689</category>
    <category>00e2b003-a2bb-49dc-9a28-56438b9612d3</category>
  </categories>
  <notifications />
</post>